Mohammad El Prince

Mississauga, ON | 519-760-1559 | mohammad-elprince@proton.me <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Github</u> | <u>Portfolio</u>

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Full Stack Software Engineer with experience in JavaScript and Python based programming. With a background in mechanical engineering and operations, I have a can-do attitude and bring strong skills in problem-solving, communication and collaboration. As a lifelong learner, I continuously work on growing my technical knowledge. I enjoy tackling challenges head-on and crafting creative solutions to real-world problems. My belief in the power of teamwork guides me in achieving exceptional results.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, ReactJS, Next.is, Scss, SQL, VSCode, Git

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

WriteWell - GitHub | Demo | Live

WriteWell is a full-stack app that enables bloggers to share, edit, and delete blogs.

- Built with Next.js for the front end and styled with scss.
- Employed Nextis routing ability to construct endpoints for API requests.
- Utilized MySQL as the database, which is deployed on AWS RDS.
- Deployed images to AWS S3 and linked them to the database.

Portfolio - GitHub | Demo | Live

A digital showcase of my professional journey, highlighting my skills and projects.

- Employed HTML, CSS, and JavaScript showcasing my abilities to learn and in front-end web development and design.
- Incorporated interactive elements and animation using JS and CSS
- Maintained DRY coding following best practices in all the project files

GPT-3 Intro - GitHub | Live

A landing page created to describe GPT-3 technology that provides a brief introduction about this modern AI technology.

- Built with ReactJS and CSS styling showcasing an appealing user experience.
- Utilized BEM (Block Element Modifier) technique to relate JSX elements to styling.
- Deployed JSON server as the backend server.

Budget Tracker CLI - GitHub | Demo

A command-line application designed to help you manage your finances and track your expenses easily.

- Employed python scripts and functions and maintained DRY coding
- Utilized SQLAlchemy for database management.
- Implemented the rich library for a user-friendly CL interface.

RECENT PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Amazon, Hamilton/St. Thomas/London/Mississauga, ON

05/2021 - Present

Lead Fulfillment Associate/Field Quality Assurance

- Manage 50+ Associates across Amazon Robotics (AR) floor and inventory workstations.
- Monitor the health of four Amazon Robotics floors, each 135x235 square meters, for optimal productivity and safe operation.
- Train Level1 Leads and provide coverage for other managers.

Master of Science — Mechanical Engineering (Thesis-based)

Bachelor of Science — Mechanical Engineering (course-based)

University of Guelph, Guelph, ON

01/2019 - 05/2021

09/2016 - 12/2018

01/2012 - 05/2016

Teaching/Research Assistant

- Lectured large groups of students (75 150 students) on fundamental engineering courses and proctored exams.
- Conducted experimental and theoretical research in the areas of gas wells and safety of nuclear power plants.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School Full Stack Web Development, Python and JavaScript online program	02/2023 - 10/2023
University of Guelph, Guelph, ON Master of Engineering — Mechanical Engineering (course-based)	01/2019 – 02/2021
King Fahd University of Petroleum and Minerals, Dhahran, KSA	